Guide to the Herman F. Mark Collection, 1918-2013 RG.002
Poly Archives at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
- Series VII: Photographs
  - Subseries B: Family and Friends
    - Portraits and group photos, 1927-1929; undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Family portrait reproductions (photograph, slide, photocopy), undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Group military portrait and negative, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Maria Mark (Mimi), 1938; undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Herman and Maria Mark with friends, 1953, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Hans Mark, Peter Mark, and Mark grandchildren, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Herman Mark with grandson Rufus and family, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Family and Friends, 1990s (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Family and Friends in Texas, 1990s (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Subseries C: Students and Colleagues
    - Israeli President Ephraim Katzir, 1976; undated (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Professor Frederick Eirich, undated (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Professor Murray Goodman, 1974 January 17 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Dr. Jack B. Nagler (former student), 1991 August 27 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Lingyu He (visiting scholar), 1990 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Bruno Zimm and Paul Doty, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Mark in his office and lab with colleagues, 1980s (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Professional associates, undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Mark with Students (includes negatives), undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Subseries D: Events
    - Herman Mark Bust dedication, with sculptor Jimilu Mason, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - American Chemical Society meetings, 1968, undated (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Willard Gibbs Medal, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - National Medal of Science, with President Jimmy Carter, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Wolf Prize, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Heity Foundation Dinner, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - 100 Shares of Montecatini stock to PIB, undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 80th Birthday Celebration contact sheets, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - 90th Birthday Celebration, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Birthday Celebrations, miscellaneous, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Polyethylene Demonstration, undated (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Lectures, undated (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Events, miscellaneous (black and white), 1947-1986 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Events, miscellaneous (color), 1983; undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous
    - Travels, 1956-1966 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Travels, 1980-1984 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Mountains, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Herman and Maria Mark's gravestone, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - NASA, 1976-1982 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Subseries F: Negatives
    - Negatives, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Subseries G: Albums
    - OMV Aktiengesellschaft, undated (Box 23.5, Item 1)
    - Award reception, undated (Box 23.5, Item 2)
    - Poly event, undated (Box 23.5, Item 3)
  - Subseries H: Slides, undated
    - Bio, undated (Box 24, Object 1)
    - CGO, undated (Box 24, Object 2)
    - China, undated (Box 24, Object 3)
    - China CCCP, undated (Box 24, Object 4)
    - Comfort, undated (Box 24, Object 5)
    - Comp, undated (Box 24, Object 6)
    - Fibers Res., undated (Box 24, Object 7)
    - For Peter 80th, undated (Box 24, Object 8)
    - Herman K (empty box), undated (Box 24, Object 9)
    - [illegible] History USA, undated (Box 24, Object 10)
    - Luiz Schleiniger- Photographer, undated (Box 24, Object 11)
    - Medical, undated (Box 24, Object 12)
    - Medical Reserve, undated (Box 24, Object 13)
    - Novophalt, undated (Box 24, Object 14)
    - Perkin Ivitrene (Box 24, Object 15)
    - Peter Color, 1958 (Box 24, Object 16)
    - Photos, undated (Box 24, Object 17)
    - Supra, undated (Box 24, Object 18)
    - Synthetic Paper, undated (Box 24, Object 19)
- Series VIII: Framed and Oversize Photographs and Documents
  - Subseries A: Artwork
    - Herman Mark Portrait, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 1)
    - Unidentified portrait of a man by W.W, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 2)
    - Painting of a woman with blue eyes and wool scarf, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 3)
    - Herman Mark Writing on Chalkboard, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 4)
    - Print of a castle, Schlofshof au Heidelberg, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 5)
  - Subseries B: Photographs
    - Herman Mark holding glasses, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 6)
    - Murray Goodman, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 7)
    - Herman Mark wearing glasses, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 8)
    - Group photograph, National Chemical Laboratory India, 1962 April 25 (Box Oversize 31, Item 9)
    - Unidentified Man, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 10)
    - Charlie with the note to GHR, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 11)
    - Herman Mark grandchildren (two girls, 1 boy), undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 12)
    - Herman Mark and Rudorfer, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 13)
    - Landscape of mountains and a river, undated (Box Oversize 31, Item 14)
  - Subseries C: Awards and Honors
    - The Elliott Cressin Medal,The Franklin Institute of the State of Pennsylvania for the promotion of the mechanic arts, 1966 October 19 (Box Oversize 32, Item 1)
    - Charles Goodyear Medal, Rubber Division of American Chemical Society, 1988 (Box Oversize 32, Item 2)
    - CCCP Bobetckhx, 1966 (Box Oversize 32, Item 3)
    - The Olney Medal of the American Association of Textile Chemist and Colorist endowed by the Howes publishing company, 1965 (Box Oversize 32, Item 4)
    - The Commonwealth of Kentucky, Commission to Kentucky Colonel, 1983 March 3 (Box Oversize 32, Item 5)
    - Plastic Institute of America for Polymer Science and Education, 1965 January 22 (Box Oversize 32, Item 6)
    - IBM Update '77, 1977 July 31-August 26 (Box Oversize 32, Item 7)
    - American Chemical Society Award in Polymer Chemistry, 1965 April 5 (Box Oversize 32, Item 8)
    - General Electric Modern Engineering, Crotonville, NY, 1963 Spring (Box Oversize 32, Item 9)
    - General Electric Modern Engineering, Saratoga Springs, NY, 1962 Fall (Box Oversize 32, Item 10)
    - Czechoslovak Academy of Sciences, 1988 February 25 (Box Oversize 33, Item 1)
    - The National Medal of Science, 1979 (Box Oversize 33, Item 2)
    - Croatian Plastic Company (Croatian), 1974 January 17 (Box Oversize 33, Item 3)
    - The Wolf Foundation Prize, Israel, 1979 (Box Oversize 33, Item 4)
    - Celebration of Herman's advancement of polymeric materials and chemical fibers, 1975 May 3 (Box Oversize 33, Item 5)
    - Sarnia Lecture in Science of the Chemical Institute of Canada, 1967 January 11 (Box Oversize 33, Item 6)
    - The Association of Austrian Plastic Processors, 1981 May 11 (Box Oversize 33, Item 7)
    - The Wayne State Polymer Conference Series, 1968 (Box Oversize 33, Item 8)
    - Council of Long Island Technical Societies Certificate of Appreciation, 1963 May 7 (Box Oversize 33, Item 9)
    - Unidentified award in Arabic, 1974 (Box Oversize 34, Item 1)
    - Aachen University of Applied Sciences, 1975 June 23 (Box Oversize 34, Item 2)
    - The Silver Medal of Honor of CIFRS, Paris, 1980 September (Box Oversize 34, Item 3)
    - Israel Plastics Society, 1975 July 13 (Box Oversize 34, Item 4)
    - AJ Bert A Michelson Edwa D.W Moriex Award, Case Western Reserve University, 1989 April 28 (Box Oversize 34, Item 5)
    - Chemical Pioneer Award,The American Institute of Chemists, 1972 May 20 (Box Oversize 34, Item 6)
    - Honorary Fellow at National Institute of Sciences of India, 1952 January 1 (Box Oversize 34, Item 7)
    - Distinguished Lecture Award, University of Massachusetts, 1984 January (Box Oversize 34, Item 8)
    - Fellow, International Academy of Woods Science, 1968 July 2 (Box Oversize 34, Item 9)
    - Named 'Father of Polymer Chemistry' by the American Chemical Society, 1985 May 3 (Box Oversize 34, Item 10)
  - Subseries D: Honorary Degrees
    - University of Massachusetts, 1982 July 12 (Box Oversize 35, Item 1)
    - University of Massachusetts, 1982 July 12 (Box Oversize 35, Item 2)
    - The Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1965 June 9 (Box Oversize 35, Item 3)
    - Gh. Asachi Polytechnic Institute of Iasi (Romanian), 1971 May 29 (Box Oversize 35, Item 4)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Iasi (Romanian), 1972 October 16 (Box Oversize 35, Item 5)
    - The Technical College in Wine (German), 1965 November (Box Oversize 35, Item 6)
    - The Technical University of Munich (German), 1960 February 24 (Box Oversize 35, Item 7)
    - Universitas Longinsvlanae, 1976 June 11 (Box Oversize 35, Item 8)
    - Elutonoma University of Madrid (Spanish), 1973 June 25 (Box Oversize 35, Item 9)
    - Claude Bernard University (French), 1986 September 3 (Box Oversize 35, Item 10)
    - University of Nottingham, 1980 July 10 (Box Oversize 35, Item 11)
  - Subseries E: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn
    - Well wishes from Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, undated (Box Oversize 36, Item 1)
    - Presentation Committee, 1960 March 12 (Box Oversize 36, Item 2)
    - Presentation Committee (duplicate), 1960 March 12 (Box Oversize 36, Item 3)
    - The President's Associates of the Annual Fund of Polytechnic Institute of New York, 1982 October 6 (Box Oversize 36, Item 4)
    - Celebration of the establishment of the Alstadt, Lord, Mark Chair in the Natural Sciences, 1968 February 21 (Box Oversize 36, Item 5)
  - Subseries F: Memberships
    - Die Osterreichische Akademie der Wissenschaften, 1970 May 26 (Box Oversize 36, Item 6)
    - Japanese Membership Certificate, 1972 May 25 (Box Oversize 36, Item 7)
    - The Association of Chemical industry, Honorary Member (German), 1980 June 26 (Box Oversize 36, Item 8)
    - American Institute of Chemists, Life Fellow, 1978 April 13 (Box Oversize 36, Item 9)
    - Plastic Institute of America, Member for Life, 1965 January 22 (Box Oversize 36, Item 10)
    - The National Academy of Science, 1961 April 25 (Box Oversize 36, Item 11)
    - Chemist Club of New York, Honorary member, 1976 December 29 (Box Oversize 36, Item 12)
    - The New York Academy of Science, Honorary Life Member, 1977 December 8 (Box Oversize 36, Item 13)
    - The New York Academy of Science, Honorary Life Member, undated (Box Oversize 36, Item 14)
    - American Society fo Prominent Americans and International Notables, Member of Eminent Distinction, 1978-1979 (Box Oversize 36, Item 15)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, Fifty Year Member, 1989 July 28 (Box Oversize 36, Item 16)
  - Subseries G: Birthday
    - 80th birthday wishes from the XXIV IUPAC Symposium on Macromolecules (in Hebrew), 1975 (Box Oversize 37, Item 1)
    - 80th birthday from the GdCh Macromolecular Chemistry Specialist Group (in German), 1975 May (Box Oversize 37, Item 2)
    - 80th birthday wishes from the High Polymer Laboratory I.A.C.S Calcutta- India, 1975 (Box Oversize 37, Item 3)
    - 80th birthday wishes from Professor Cristotor Gimionescu, 1975 April 15 (Box Oversize 37, Item 4)
    - 80th birthday wishes from the Polish Academy of Science Center for Molecular and Macromolecular Studies, 1975 (Box Oversize 37, Item 5)
    - 80th birthday wishes from the Polytechnic Institute of New York, 1974 May 3 (Box Oversize 37, Item 6)
    - 90th birthday wishes from the Ronald Reagan, 1985 April 24 (Box Oversize 37, Item 7)
  - Subseries H: Newspapers
    - New York Times Vol XLIV (44) NO 13634, 1895 May 3 (Box Oversize 37, Item 8)
    - Weiner Beitang, 1895 May 3 (Box Oversize 37, Item 9)
  - Subseries I: Conservation needed-- these items are closed to researchers (Box Oversize 38)
- Series IX: Magnetic Media
  - Subseries A: Video tapes: Interviews and Ceremonies
    - American Chemical Society Interview with Dr. Herman F. Mark, Dr. Charles Overberger, interviewer (part 1 of 2), 1981; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 1)
    - American Chemical Society Interview with Dr. Herman F. Mark, Dr. Charles Overberger, interviewer (part 2 of 2), 1981; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 2)
    - Eminent Chemists: H. Mark Interviewed by C. Overberger (part 1 of 2), undated; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 3)
    - Eminent Chemists Videotape Series: Dr. Herman F. Mark, undated; U-matic Runtime 46:10 (Box 25, Object 4)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      To view the digitized video, contact the Poly Archives.
    - H. Mark Interviewed by C. Overberger (part 2 of 2), undated; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 5)
    - Herman Mark, undated; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 6)
      tape length
      00:56:45
    - Presidential Ceremony Honoring the 1979 Medal of Science Awardees, 1980 January 14; U-matic Run time: approximately 20 minutes (Box 25, Object 7)
  - Subseries B: Video Tapes: Polymer Research
    - The Development of Early Polymer Chemistry in America -- The Early Years: Carl S. Marvel, 1980; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 8)
    - MRS - Frontiers in Materials Research: Recent Advances in Polymers - H. Mark, 1989; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 9)
    - Polymer Science: Visions and Perspectives 1 of 2, 1999; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 10)
    - Polymer Science: Visions and Perspectives 2 of 2, 1999; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 11)
    - H. Mark PRI [Polymer Research Institute], undated; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 12)
      00:07:00
  - Subseries C: Video tapes: Scientific Topics
    - Herman Mark: Early 20th Century Physics (1), Probably 1979; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 13)
    - Herman Mark: Fibers (3), 1979; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 14)
    - Herman Mark: Rubber (4), 1979; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 15)
    - Herman Mark: Polymers and the Environment (5), 1979; VHS tapes (Box 25, Object 16)
    - Herman F. Mark: Aviation - Fire, 1983; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 17)
  - Subseries D: 3M Magnetic Tapes
    - Polymers Part III, 1968 March 9 (Box 26, Object 1)
    - H. Mark Polymers, undated (Box 26, Object 2)
    - H. Mark Polymers, undated (Box 26, Object 3)
  - Subseries E: Audio tapes and 740 diskettes
    - Lord Corporation's Symposium tapes, 1989 October 3-4 (Box 26, Object 4)
    - "Dimensions in Science" American Chemical Society, circa 1985 (Box 26, Object 5)
    - Mark II, undated (Box 26, Object 6)
    - Mark III, undated (Box 26, Object 7)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 26, Object 8)
    - H. Mark 740 diskette (Scotch 3M), undated (Box 26, Object 9)
    - Mark 740 diskette (IBM), undated (Box 26, Object 10)
    - Chemistry Mark 740 diskette (IBM), undated (Box 26, Object 11)
- Series X: Personal items and Miscellaneous
  - Subseries A: Desk drawer realia
    - Portable 3-Dimensional Joke Kit (actually contains spices), undated (Box 27, Object 1)
    - Fulton Rubber Type Outift, undated (Box 27, Object 2)
    - ABC rubber stamp kit, undated (Box 27, Object 3)
    - North America Steel Company magnifying glass (Box 27, Object 4)
    - Set of three keys, undated (Box 27, Object 5)
    - Set of two key fobs with "Dr. H Mark", undated (Box 27, Object 6)
    - Plastic cylinder, undated (Box 27, Object 7)
    - Plastic in petri dish labeled "Hema", undated (Box 27, Object 8)
    - Birthday candles and holders, undated (Box 27, Object 9)
    - Calculator, undated (Box 27, Object 10)
    - Metal pieces in envelope, undated (Box 27, Object 11)
    - Cologne, undated (Box 27, Object 12)
    - Polarizing film, undated (Box 27, Object 13)
    - Three beakers, undated (Box 27, Object 14)
    - Buttons in envelope, undated (Box 27, Object 15)
    - Oxford copy holder, undated (Box 27, Object 16)
    - Magnifying glass, undated (Box 27, Object 17)
  - Subseries B: Personal, financial and medical records
    - Personal (contains bank statements, correspondence, memberships), circa 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Personal 1990 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Condolences, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Symposium, regrets, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Mark Estate, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Bank statements, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Payments, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Receipts, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Tax forms and bank statements, 1991-1992 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Rents, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Taxes, 1989-1991 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Work sheets, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Bank statements, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Payments, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Receipts, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Receipts, January-April 1988 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Receipts, May-August 1988 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Receipts, September-December 1988 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Receipts, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous receipts, 1981-1990; undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Medical, 1990-1992 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Medicare, 1989-1991 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous
    - Air clubs, 1978-1992 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Maps and train timetables, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Magazines, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous documents and publications, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous documents, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Numbered ink drawing, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Herman Mark's suitcase (containing shirt, tie, and sweater), undated (Box unboxed)
    - Herman Mark's leather tote bag, undated (Box unboxed)
- Series XI: Collection provenance and information
  - Austrian National Library, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Herman Mark Collection (Heather Walters), 2001 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Herman Mark Collection (Lindsay Anderberg, Hans Mark, Jana Richman), 2013-2014 (Box 29, Folder 7)